Mss.B.B445
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 8, 1939 July - 1940 November (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Letters concerning the submission of papers to the Journal of Biological Chemistry. Includes a copy of a paper titled, "Determination of Proline In Mixtures Containing l- and dl-Proline: The Proline Content of Gelatin."
  - Journals, No. 1, 1935 April - 1936 June (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Journals, No. 1
    Letters to Max Bergmann from the journal "Current Science" requesting a submission by him.
  - Journals, No. 2, 1934 May - 1939 October (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Journals, No. 2
    Advertisements and requests for Max Bergmann to contribute to various journals including: the Journal of the American Chemical Society, Enzymologea, and Biological Abstracts.
  - Journals, No. 3, 1941 December - 1944 August (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Journals, No. 3
    Letters concerning submissions to various journals. Includes Max Bergmann's critques of several papers.
  - Journal of the American Leather Chemists Association, 1934 May - 1935 November (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Journal of the American Leather Chemists Association
    Letters to Max Bergmann asking for his opinion on several papers submitted for publication. A copy of an address given by Max Bergmann to the American Leather Chemists Association in May 1934.
  - K - Misc., No. 1, 1937 September - 1944 November (Box 11, Folder 9)
    K - Misc., No. 1
    Miscellaneous materials. Letters of reference from Max Bergmann, requests for chemical samples, and requests for reprints.
  - K - Misc., No. 2, 1934 April - April 1942 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    K - Misc., No. 2
    Miscellaneous materials. Letters requesting reprints and chemicals. Invitation to a groundbreaking ceremony. Letter seeking the advice of Max Bergmann on working with collagen.
  - K - Misc., No. 3, 1937 January - 1947 April (Box 11, Folder 11)
    K - Misc., No. 3
    Miscellaneous materials. Personal notes. Letters discussing experiments. A copy of a resume for Albert A. Kondritzer. Two letters from October 1947, after Max Bergmann's death, concerning the "latest theories in protein."
  - Kahn, Ernest, 1941 March - June (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Kahn, Ernest
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Ernest Kahn concerning employment. Includes letters of reference for Kahn.
  - Kelley, Louise, 1938 January - March (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Kelley, Louise
    Letters dicussing a paper presented by Max Bergmann at the Richmond Organic Symposium titled, "Protein Structure in Relation to Biological Problems."
  - Kennedy, Norman F., 1941 July - September (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Kennedy, Norman F.
    Notice of meeting for the Round Table of Starch Chemists.
  - Kidd, John G., 1939 May - 1942 July (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Kidd, John G.
    Letter informing Max Bergmann of demonstrations to take place in his lab for the "Third International Congress of Microbiologists" held by the Rockefeller Institute. Note of congratulations to John Kidd on becoming a member of the Institute.
  - King, C. G., 1937 August - 1940 February (Box 11, Folder 16)
    King, C. G.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and C. G. King. King recommends a David Glick to Bergmann. Bergmann writes letters of reference for Sam A. Morrell and Carl Nieman for nomination to the American Society of Biological Chemists.
  - Kintzinger, Peter, 1939 November - 1940 January (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Kintzinger, Peter
    Letter to Max Bergmann seeking advice on job prospects in the United States for a Siegbert Stein, who was interned as a POW in England.
  - Klanfer, Karl, 1935 August - 1940 December (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Klanfer, Karl
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Karl Klanfer. Letters mainly discuss Klanfer's being interned in a German Jewish internment camp in Canada.
  - Knopf, Martin, 1941 March - May (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Knopf, Martin
    Letters concerning employment for Knopf, a German refugee, as an agricultural chemist in the United States. Includes letter of recommendation written by Max Bergmann.
  - Knöpfler, Josef, 1938 December - 1939 March (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Knöpfler, Josef
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Knöpfler concerning job prospects in the United States. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Koch, F. C., 1939 November - 1940 May (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Koch, F. C.
    A letter inviting Max Bergmann to do a lecture course at the University of Chicago in the summer of 1940. A letter from Max Bergmann introducing Dr. Chi-yuan Chou.
  - Kocholaty, Walter, 1937 November - 1943 December (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Kocholaty, Walter
    Letters concerning job prospects for Kocholaty. Curriculum vitae included. Requests for chemical samples.
  - Kögl, F., 1939 October - December (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Kögl, F.
    Requests for reprints.
  - Koenigsberger, F., 1939 January - October (Box 11, Folder 24)
    Koenigsberger, Franz
    Curriculum vitae. Letter from Max Bergmann recommending Dr. Fransisca Stern and Dr. Bruno Rewald.
  - Kohn, Moritz, 1941 June - 1944 May (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Kohn, Moritz
    Correspondence regarding the situation of German refugee Moritz Kohn. Bergmann advises Kohn to go to Cuba and then helps him gain entry into the United States. Bergmann also writes to the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars in an attempt to find work for Kohn. Includes a sample of the 1941 VISA application forms.
  - Kuffner, P. K., 1940 September (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Kuffner, P. K.
    A letter of introduction to Max Bergmann from a Dr. Lowenfeld.
  - Kuttner, Ann G., 1941 December (Box 11, Folder 27)
    Kuttner, Ann G.
    Directions for the preparation of collagen.
  - Kunitz, Moses, 1938 March - 1941 November (Box 11, Folder 28)
    Kunitz, Moses
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Moses Kunitz. Letters discuss the preparation of chemicals and requests for samples.
  - L - Misc., No. 1, 1936 September - 1945 February (Box 12, Folder 1)
    L - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters of reference. Letters of recommendation. Requests for reprints. Requests for chemicals. Notes of thanks. A curriculum vitae for George Laemmle.
  - L - Misc., No. 2, 1934 May - 1946 January (Box 12, Folder 2)
    L - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous materials. Notes of thanks. Requests for reprints. A copy of an abstract of a book titled, "Microbiology of Raw Hides." Letters requesting a position working in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - L - Misc., No. 3, 1935 May - 1944 March (Box 12, Folder 3)
    L - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters concerning employment in Max Bergmann's lab. Requests for reprints. Personal notes.
  - L - Misc., No. 4, 1934 June - 1942 August (Box 12, Folder 4)
    L - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous materials. Letter of recommendation for Robert Ballentine. Letters of reference. Notes of congratulations. Requests for reprints.
  - Lachow, Ruth, 1944 August - November (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Lachow, Ruth
    Letters requesting a meeting with Max Bergmann. Letters postponing due to Bergmann's illness.
  - Ladenburg, R., 1936 December - 1939 January (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Ladenburg, Rudolf
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Rudolf Ladenburg.
  - Lalor Foundation, 1939 January (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Lalor Foundation
    Letters of recommendation for Sidney Fox and Otto K. Behrens.
  - Lamb, Arthur B., 1941 February - July (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Lamb, Arthur B.
    Letters asking Max Bergmann to referee two papers for the Journal of the American Chemical Society.
  - Lampen, J. Oliver, 1944 October (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Lampen, J. Oliver
    Requests for chemicals.
  - Landsteiner, Karl, 1941 January - 1942 October (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Landsteiner, Karl
    Letters exchanging references about chemical reactions and production methods of certain chemicals.
  - Lang, Friedrich, 1940 March - May (Box 12, Folder 11)
    Lang, Friedrich
    Personal correspondence. Letters discussing a process which Lang would like to patent.
  - Lange, Willy, 1938 April - 1942 July (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Lange, Willy
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Willy Lange. Bergmann writes Lange asking to help find a job for Dr. Victor Sanders. Lange writes Bergmann seeking recommendations for chemists to work in his lab. Includes the curriculum vitae of Lange.
  - Langmuir, Irving, 1937 January - 1938 July (Box 12, Folder 13)
    Langmuir, Irving
    Letters requesting samples. Langmuir forwards a copy of an article by Dorothy Wrinch.
  - Lantern Slides, 1941 December (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Lantern Slides
    Notes and images from a lecture on December 19, 1941. Includes duplicates of the slides used, two lantern slides, and lecture notes.
  - Lantern Slides: Washington Lecture, 1942 November 12 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Lantern Slides: Washington Lecture
    Lecture notes and images from lantern slides.
  - Laskowski, Michael, 1941 August - 1944 May (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Laskowski, Michael
    General correspondence between max Bergmann and Michael Laskowski. Laskowski writes to Bergmann requesting advice and the use of his lab equipment.
  - Leather Samples, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Leather Samples
    Physical samples and photographic images of leather.
  - Lecture at the Seventh National Organic Chemistry Symposium of the American Chemical Society, 1937 December 29 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Lecture at the Seventh National Organic Chemistry Symposium of the American Chemical Society
    Copy of a lecture given by Max Bergmann titled, "The Structure of Proteins in Relation to Biological Problems."
  - Lectures, 1942 January - 1944 April (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Lectures
    Notes on various lectures both given and attended.
  - Levene, P. A., No. 1, 1944 January - July (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Levene, P. A., No. 1
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Mrs. P. A. Levene during Bergmann's illness.
  - Levene, P. A., No. 2, 1935 May - 1940 March (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Levene, P. A., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and P. A. Levene. Levene asks Bergmann to discuss with him and H. T. Clarke the possibility of forming a Committee on Protein ACS. A list of the members of the committee. Letters of opion regarding the committee. Letters of recommendation. Requests fro reprints and chemicals.
  - Levene, P. A., No. 3, 1942 March - 1944 November (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Levene, P. A., No. 3
    Letters concerning samples of chemicals from P. A. Levene's collection.
  - Lewis, Howard B., 1937 December - 1938 December (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Lewis, Howard B.
    Letters discuss plans for Max Bergmann to give a series of lectures at the Medical School at the University of Michigan.
  - Li, Choh Hao, 1944 April - September (Box 12, Folder 24)
    Li, Choh Hao
    Letters concerning chemical samples from Max Bergmann's lab.
  - Linderstrom-Lang, K., 1937 March - 1940 December (Box 12, Folder 25)
    Linderstrom-Lang, K.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Linderstrom-Lang. Letters asking Bergmann to contribute to the jubilee volume for the seventieth birthday of Dr. S. P. L. Sorensen. Linderstrom-Lang offers his assistance to Bergmann on his trip to Denmark in March, 1939. Linderstrom-Lang recommends Godfred Haugaard to work in Bergmann's lab. A letter from Bergmann frowarding one of Lindestrom-Lang's papers to the journal of Biological Chemistry.
  - Link, Karl Paul, No. 1, 1944 January - November (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Link, Karl Paul, No. 1
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Karl Paul Link.
  - Link, Karl Paul, No. 2, 1942 September - 1943 April (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Link, Karl Paul, No. 2
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Karl Paul Link. Includes letter of recommendation, postcards, invitations, and letters concerning Bergmann's work.
  - Link, Karl Paul, No. 3, 1939 May - 1942 August (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Link, Karl Paul, No. 3
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Karl Paul Link. Letters concerning the development of war. Copy of a lecture given by Link in Wisconsin in October, 1936. Recommendations for Carl Niemann to the American Society of Biological Chemists.
  - Link, Karl Paul, No. 4, 1940 June (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Link, Karl Paul, No. 4
    Letter of recommendation and curriculum vitae for David Doherty.
  - Link, Karl Paul, No. 5, 1935 December - 1940 May (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Link, Karl Paul, No. 5
  - Link, Karl Paul, No. 6, 1935 January - 1940 December (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Link, Karl Paul, No. 6
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Karl Paul Link. Letters of recommendation. Invitations. Plans for visits.
  - Lipschitz, Werner, 1937 March - 1940 May (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Lipschitz, Werner
    Letters from Max Bergmann to Lipschitz giving the advice requested for publishing a paper.
  - Loewenfeld, Philipp, 1940 September (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Loewenfeld, Philipp
    Lowenfield writes to Max Bergmann on behalf of Baron Peter Kuffner (German leather chemist) who is looking for a job in the United States.
  - Loewi, Otto, 1941 April - 1944 April (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Loewi, Otto
    Letters from Max Bergmann to Loewi discussing reprints, references, and books. Letter from Bergmann asking Loewi if he is related to a Ludwig Lowy, a refugee that Bergmann is trying to help.
  - Löwy, Ludwig, 1940 May - 1941 April (Box 13, Folder 10)
    Löwy, Ludwig
    Letters concerning Löwy's attempt to come to the United States.
  - Loyalty Committee of Victims of Nazi-Fascist Oppression, 1942 April - July (Box 13, Folder 11)
    Loyalty Committee of Victims of Nazi-Fascist Oppression
    Letters discussing the importance of the organization. Includes letters between Arthur Cohn and Herbert H. Lehman (Governor of New York) illustrating examples of the support the organization is recieving.
  - Lucas, C. C., 1934 April - 1936 February (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Lucas, C. C.
    Requests for reprints. Invitation for Max Bergmann to address the Toronto Chemical Society.
  - Luck, J. Murray, No. 1, 1938 June - 1939 June (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Luck, J. Murray, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Luck. Bergmann writes a letter of recommendation for Dr. Heinz Fraenkal-Conrat.
  - Luck, J. Murray, No. 2, 1939 October - 1943 June (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Luck, J. Murray, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Luck. Discussion about Bergmann's position as a reviewer for the Annual Review of Biochemistry. Arrangements for Bergmann to give a lecture at Harvard University.
  - Ludewig, Stephen, 1934 August - 1942 July (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Ludewig, Stephen
    Letters cocerning the employment of a Dr. Mestern.
  - Lupinek, Bernard, 1941 May (Box 13, Folder 16)
    Lupinek, Bernard
    Letters to Lupinek (carpenter at Rockefeller Institute) arranging several jobs.
  - M - Misc., No. 1, 1936 May - 1947 October (Box 13, Folder 17)
    M - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials. Includes letters of recommendation, requests for reprints, letters discussing experiments, and requests for samples.
  - M - Misc., No. 2, 1934 February - 1945 July (Box 13, Folder 18)
    M - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous materials. Inlcudes letters of recommendation, requests for reprints, letters concerning positions in Max Bergmann's lab, and an inventory of the special equipment in Bergmann's lab.
  - M - Misc., No. 3, 1936 October - 1944 October (Box 13, Folder 19)
    M - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters requesting samples and reprints. Letters seeking the advice of Max Bergmann regarding experimental procedures.
  - M - Misc., No. 4, 1942 March - November (Box 13, Folder 20)
    M - Misc., No. 4
    Letters concerning employment in Max Bergmann's lab.
  - M - Misc., No. 5, 1934 September - 1944 March (Box 13, Folder 21)
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters requesting reprints. Notes of thanks. Invitations to speaking engagements. Letters of reference.
  - McCollum, E. V., 1938 February - May (Box 13, Folder 22)
    McCollum, E. V.
    Letter asking Max Bergmann's permission to use one of his tables in a book.
  - MacInnes, Duncan A., 1941 October - 1943 December (Box 13, Folder 23)
    MacInnes, Duncan A.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Duncan MacInnes. Letters of recommendation. Requests for lab equipment. A note of congratulations to MacInnes on being awarded a Nichols Medal.
  - McShan, W. H., 1938 May - November (Box 13, Folder 24)
    McShan, W. H.
    Letters requesting samples of chemicals from Max Bergmann.
  - Mai, K., 1941 August - September (Box 13, Folder 25)
    Mai, K.
    Letter requesting Max Bergmann's help for her father in Germany.
  - Major, Randolph T., 1940 December (Box 13, Folder 26)
    Major, Randolph T.
    Letter to Max Bergmann concerning the possibility of Bergmann recommending a good chemist to work in Major's lab.
  - Malisoff, William Marias, 1941 March - September (Box 13, Folder 27)
    Malisoff, William Marias
    Letter requesting Max Bergmann's assistance in editing the "Dictionary of Biochemistry."
  - Marcuse, Reinhard, 1940 March - November (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Marcuse, Reinhard
    Correspondence concerning the procurment of a visa for Marcuse.
  - Mark, H., 1938 February - March (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Mark, H.
    Invitation and program to the International Conference for Holzverwertung in Vienna in July, 1939.
  - Markowitz, Maurice, 1944 October - April (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Markowitz, Maurice
  - Marvel, C. S., 1942 July - 1944 March (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Marvel, C. S.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Marvel. Bergmann writes to Marvel for a recommendation for someone to work in his lab. A note of congratulations from Bergmann to Marvel on his being awarded a Nichols Medal.
  - Marx, Walter, 1939 June - 1943 November (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Marx, Walter
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Walter Marx. Marx writes to Bergmann asking him to introduce him to Carl Niemann. Curriculum vitae for Marx.
  - Maschmann, E., 1936 August - 1940 February (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Maschmann, E.
    Letters seeking Max Bergmann's advice on experiments. Requests for reprints.
  - Matthes, O., 1934 May - July (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Matthes, O.
    Letters from Max Bergmann requesting samples of "Salzstippen" leather.
  - Mayer, Lola, 1940 June - October (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Mayer, Lola
    List of books available on Germany.
  - Mayer, Manfred M., 1944 July - September (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Mayer, Manfred M.
    Mayer writes to Max Bergmann, at the suggestion of Dr. Michael Heidelberger at Columbia, asking to work in Bergmann's lab for one year.
  - Mearl Corporation, 1938 September - December (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Mearl Corporation
    Letters discussing the prices of arginine.
  - Melville, J., 1934 November - 1938 December (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Melville, J.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Melville. Includes a letter of introduction for Melville from H. B. Vickery.
  - Menkin, Valy, 1937 November - 1938 November (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Menkin, Valy
    Letters discussing Max Bergmann's advice regarding an experiment. Request of reprints.
  - Merck and Company, 1935 December - 1945 April (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Merck and Company
    Letters of recommendation. Chemical orders. Requests of reprints.
  - Merrill, Alice T., 1943 October - November (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Merrill, Alice T.
    Letter to Max Bergmann concerning employment oppurtunities in the sugar chemical industry. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Methods, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Methods
    References to other entries in the collection regarding methods for various procedures.
  - Metsomäki, Arvo, 1938 April (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Metsomäki, Arvo
    Letters discussing the results of an experiment.
  - Meyer, Hans, 1941 September - 1943 September (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Meyer, Hans
    Letter to Max Bergmann seeking his help for the immigration of his brother from Europe.
  - Meyer, Dr. Herbert, 1943 June - 1945 December (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Meyer, Dr. Herbert
    Correspondence concerning the employment of Meyer. Curriculum vitae sent to Max Bergmann via the "Selfhelp of Emigres From Central Europe Inc."
  - Meyer, Lothar, 1941 October - November (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Meyer, Lothar
    Letters discussing the possible immigration of Lothar Meyer from Europe. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Meyerhof, Otto, 1940 July - 1943 February (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Meyerhof, Otto
    A letter to Max Bergmann explaining Meyerhof's situation in Europe and his desperate need to escape to the United States. A response from Bergmann to Meyerhof written in code to evade the scrutiny of inspectors.
  - Michaelis, Leonor, 1943 May - November (Box 14, Folder 21)
    Michaelis, Leonor
    A letter thanking Max Bergmann for chemicals he sent.
  - Miekeley, Arthur, 1934 May - June (Box 14, Folder 22)
    Miekeley, Arthur
    Max Bergmann sends a bill for a lecture he gave in England while in the employ of the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute.
  - Miller, Edgar G., Jr., 1937 November (Box 14, Folder 23)
    Miller, Edgar G., Jr.
    Letters discussing the final exams of a Dr. Stein.
  - Miller, H. M., 1936 July - 1939 April (Box 14, Folder 24)
    Miller, H. M.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and H. M. Miller. Letters of recommendation and references.
  - Miller, Lila, 1938 October - 1940 December (Box 14, Folder 25)
    Miller, Lila
    Letters discussing the details of several experiments. Requests for reprints.
  - Minibeck, D. H., 1940 May - June (Box 14, Folder 26)
    Minibeck, D. H.
    Letter requesting chemical reprints from Max Bergmann.
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1941 May - June (Box 14, Folder 27)
    Moe, Henry Allen
    Correspondence concerning the work of Dr. Rocha e Silva.
  - Montani, Angelo, 1940 December - 1941 January (Box 14, Folder 28)
    Montani, Angelo
    Letters concerning employment in the United States. Max Bergmann forwards Montani's information to the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars.
  - Moore, Stanford, No. 1, 1937 December - 1944 September (Box 14, Folder 29)
    Moore, Stanford, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Stanford Moore. Letters are both professional and personal. Includes abstracts of research undertaken by Moore.
  - Moore, Stanford, No. 2, 1946 March - 1947 January (Box 14, Folder 30)
    Moore, Stanford, No. 2
    Letters to and from Stanford Moore after he became head of Max Bergmann's lab after Bergmann's death.
  - Moore, Stanford, No. 3, 1941 August - 1944 March (Box 14, Folder 31)
    Moore, Stanford, No. 3
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Stanford Moore.
  - Morell, Samuel A., 1934 May - 1940 November (Box 14, Folder 32)
    Morell, Samuel A.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Samuel Morell. A letter requesting a position in Bergmann's lab. Bergmann writes to the American Society of Biological Chemists on behalf of Morell.
  - Mount Sinai Hospital, 1944 January - February (Box 14, Folder 33)
    Mount Sinai Hospital
    Letters of thanks from Max Bergmann to the staff of Mt. Sinai Hospital after his stay there.
  - Mueller, John Howard, 1937 March - 1943 December (Box 14, Folder 34)
    Mueller, John Howard
    Letter from Max Bergmann to Mueller introducing Sidney Fox. Letters discussing experiments.
  - Muller, Hermann Joseph, 1938 December - 1942 April (Box 14, Folder 35)
    Muller, Hermann Joseph
    Muller invites Max Bergmann to speak at the "Seventh Annual Congress of Genetics" in August, 1939. A note of thanks for reprints sent.
  - Murray, Thomas F., Jr, 1938 July - 1939 June (Box 14, Folder 36)
    Murray, Thomas F., Jr